"sekkaku hareta kara" tte iiwake o hitotsu houri nage
"The sun's finally out", I shout out an excuse
gareeji kara ikioi makase tobidashita
and fly out of the garage eagerly
mokutekichi wa minami e
I head south, pedaling hard toward the ocean
fumikonde iku pedaru wa umi no hou
chizu nante minai kimerareta you na ruuto wa iya
I don't want to take a route that
I already know without looking at a map
dareka no wadachi wa ashi ga torarete komaru
Following someone else's well-worn path
will only slow me down
isshinfuran ni egaku icchokusen rain wa
The straight line drawn with my heart and soul
boku ni shika mirenai panorama e tsuzuku
continues on toward a panorama that only I can see
konma ni-byou no mirai e ima o kirihiraite ike!
Unlock the present into a 0.2 second future!
tonikaku koge
Pedal until the end
Itachi's Story – Light and Darkness:
The Pain of Living
(イタチ)父さん。
Father!
(フガク)では この件は また後日。
We'll discuss this again later.
父さん。
(フガク)任務の帰りか？ イタチ。
Father!
Returning from a mission, Itachi?
うん。
Yeah!
お前と
こうして歩くのも久しいな。
We haven't walked together
like this in a while.
俺も もう下忍。
任務があるからね。
Well, I'm a genin now...
and have I missions.
あ… そうか。
Oh, I see!
そうだな。
うちはが ここへ移ってから…。
That's right.
Since the Uchiha moved here...
GRADUATE'S INFORMATION SESSION
もう３年か。
... three years have passed.
里の辺境に追いやられ→
We were pushed to
the outskirts of the village,
うちはの権威を失墜させる
上層部のやり方に→
and the upper echelons
took away our authority...
不満を持つ声は今も根強い。
Many still voice strong dissatisfaction
towards their methods.
それは お前も知っているな？
うん…。
You're aware of that too, right?
我らは いつしか権威を取り戻し
闇の中から陽の当たる…。
We want to regain
our power one day...
and step out from
the darkness into the light—
父さん 見て。
うん？
Father, look!
ああ… うん。
ハハハ。
何が おかしい？
What's so funny?
ごめん 父さん。
父さんは うちはの顔だからね。
Sorry, Father...
You're the face of the Uchiha.
俺も一緒に歩けて 鼻が高いよ。
I'm proud to be able to
walk alongside you.
世辞を言うな。
Enough flattery...
お前の好物でも買って帰るか？
Should we get your favorite snack
on the way home?
うん！
Yeah!
DUMPLINGS
SOLD OUT TODAY
売り切れでは しかたないな。
It can't be helped
if they're all sold out...
(イズミ)イタチ君？
Itachi?
(イタチ)イズミ…。
Izumi...
(イズミ)ごめんね イタチ君。
I'm sorry, Itachi.
お父さんと一緒だったのに
よかったの？
Are you sure I didn't interrupt
you and your dad?
ああ いいんだ。
Yeah... It's okay.
久しぶりだね。
うん。
DUMPLINGS
- It's been a while.
- Yeah.
イタチ君が 下忍になって以来かな。
It's the first time since
you became a genin.
あっ ごめんね。
あのとき お祝いも何もしなくて。
That's right!
I'm sorry I didn't get you
anything for your promotion...
っていうか おめでとうも
言ってなかったよね。
I didn't even congratulate you.
本当に ごめんね。
I'm really sorry!
そんなに何度も謝らなくても。
You don't have to apologize
so much...
あの… お祝いの代わりには
ならないだろうけど→
This doesn't really qualify
as a gift.
こんなものでよかったら
１つ どう？
But if you don't mind,
won't you have one?
(イズミ)これ お母さんの好きな
だんご屋さんの三色だんごで…。
My mom loves the tri-color
dumplings from that shop.
って イタチ君みたいに
成績優秀で 忍術も体術も万能で→
But I guess someone like you
who's brilliant and
who excels in ninjutsu and taijutsu
and whizzed through the Academy...
飛び級で アカデミーを卒業しちゃう
一族自慢の男の子が→
甘いものなんて 食べないよね。
wouldn't have a sweet tooth.
ごめんね。 私ったら 勝手に…。
Sorry for just assuming...
でも せっかく出したんだから→
Well, since I opened them...
私だけでも食べようかな。
I guess I'll eat them all myself.
もしかして 食べたいの？
Don't tell me...
Do you want one?
ウフフッ。
おかしいかな？
ううん そうじゃないの。
Is it strange?
Oh no, it isn't that.
知り合って だいぶ経つけど→
I've known you for quite
some time,
イタチ君の好物なんて
知らなかったから。
but I didn't know what
your favorite foods were.
好物に 成績の上下も
男も女も関係ないだろ。
Rank and gender have
nothing to do
with what someone likes to eat.
うん そうだね。 ごめんね。
Yeah, that's true.
Sorry.
フッ ウフフフッ…。
ごめん。 ウフフッ。
I'm sorry...
だって イタチ君 写輪眼でも
出しそうな勢いだったんだもん。
It's because, Itachi...
You looked so ready
to use your Sharingan.
ウフフッ。
あ～ おかしかった。
It was funny.
もう笑わない。 ごめんね イタチ君。
Okay, I won't laugh anymore.
Sorry, Itachi!
ごめん ごめん。
お詫びに 本当に お礼をさせて。
Sorry, sorry!
Let me make it up to you.
何か欲しいものとか ないの？
Is there anything you want?
欲しいもの？
うん。
"Anything I want"?
Yeah!
《イタチ : そういえば 彼女は…》
That's right. She's...
うん。 そうだよね。
Yeah... I thought so.
でも それは
私には あげられないよ。
But that's something
I can't give you.
うん。
(テンマ)おい！
Hey!
(テンマ)次の任務だ。
いちゃついてんじゃねえぞ。
We have another mission...
Stop flirting.
いちゃついてなんて いません！
We are not flirting!
イタチ君。
Itachi...
私には あげられないけど
祈ってるよ。
I can't give them to you...
But I'll pray for you...
写輪眼 早く開眼するといいね。
I hope that your Sharingan
awakens really soon.
そのときは
おめでとうって言わせてね。
And when it does,
I'll congratulate you!
(猫バア)この前 買っていった→
How was the kunai
you bought the other day, Itachi?
クナイの使い勝手は どうだった？
イタチ。
(イタチ)はい なかなかのものでした。
Yes, it was quite amazing.
(猫バア)なかなかか…
言ってくれるねぇ。
"Quite" amazing, eh?
You're good with words.
軽量化と 切れ味を
両立させた代物だよ。
It's lightweight and
has a sharp edge.
よそで同じものを買おうとしたら
あの値段じゃ きかないよ。
You couldn't get it
anywhere else for that price.
父からも 礼を言っておけと
申しつかってます。
Father also extends his thanks.
ハァ！ 礼なんざいらないから→
I don't need your thanks...
今回の依頼料
まけてもらえないかね 隊長さん。
How about a discount on the price
of this next request, Captain?
(ユウキ)それと これとは
また別の話ですから。
That and this job
are two separate things.
そりゃそうだけどさ…。
I understand that, but...
(ユウキ)さあ！
というわけで任務だ みんな。
All right, so we have a mission.
内容は理解してるよね？
Do you understand the specifics?
わっかんねえよ 水無月先生！
猫見つけるだけだろ？
I don't get it, Minazuki Sensei!
We just have to find a cat, right?
なんで こんなもの
つけなきゃなんねえんだよ！
So why do we have to wear this?!
(シンコ)テンマは相変わらず
しゃ～しかねぇ。
Tenma, as always,
you're so sassy.
あ？ なんだよ！ 文句あんのか？
Huh?! What did you say?
You got a problem?
コラッ！ 騒ぐでない！
Hey! Pipe down!
たまきが起きるじゃろ。
You'll wake Tamaki!
依頼したのは
ただの迷い猫捜しではない。
I'm not asking you to
find a mere lost cat.
忍猫の捜索じゃ。
It's a search for a Ninja Cat.
それも 猫の集う
地底の猫魔殿じゃからな。
What's more, you'll be going
into the Den of Cats,
where cats congregate.
(シンコ)ほ～ やけん
この猫語のわかる忍具…。
That explains this Ninja Tool.
猫具？ が必要になるニャン
じゃね～。
We need this Cat Tool which allows us
to understand cat language meow?
だけどよ 諜報活動だけなら…。
Still...
If it's only intel work, why...
Huh?!
わぁ！ アンタ よう似合うとうね～！
Wow...
That really looks great on you.
テメエ…
アカデミー首席卒業の意地っつうか→
You graduated at the top
of the class at the Academy!
恥ってもんはねえのかよ！
Have you no shame?
恥？ 任務の遂行に
見た目は関係ないと思いますが。
Shame?
Appearance has no place
in undertaking a mission, does it?
あっ!?
(ユウキ)はいはい！ ケンカしないでね。
Huh?
Okay, no fighting.
これが 依頼の忍猫の写真ね。
This is the picture of the Ninja Cat
that we're looking for.
コイツは…。
This cat is...
(シンコ)ニャニャニャ～！
Meow, meow, meow!
ほんなことを ニャンちゃん
ばりおおかとニャ～！
Aww, don't say that,
you're super cute! Meow, meow.
それ付けてんだから ヘタな猫語は
いらねえっつうんだよ。
You're wearing that thing,
so cut it out with the cat-talk.
そもそも方言きっついんだから
よりわかんねえだろ。
It's even harder to understand,
especially with your heavy accent.
んだよ！
What?!
に… 任務なんだから
しかたねえだろ！
It's a mission,
so it can't be helped!
ったく… 一族の恥だぜ。
That being said, this is
an embarrassment to my clan...
そげんことば言って
バリバリ似合うとうや～ん！
You say that,
– Hey Shinko! What's so funny?!
– but it looks so cute on you!
何がおかしい？ バカにしやがって！
(ユウキ)はいはい！
All right! All right!
まずは 情報収集。
First, let's gather intel.
僕とイタチ テンマとシンコの
二班に分かれるよ。
We'll split into two teams.
Itachi and me,
and Tenma with Shinko.
散！
Scatter!
チッ。
俺たちもいくぞ。
Let's get going too!
BLACK TORTISE DISTRICT
RING DISTRICT
HOT SPRINGS
DEN CAVES
WHITE RESTAURANT
意外に早くわかったな。
That was pretty quick.
イタチ テンマたちと合流しよう。
Let's rendezvous with Tenma and Shinko.
わかりました 呼んできます。
All right. I'll go get them.
で どげんしたと？
So what's the matter?
どげんもこげんもねえよ。
It's nothing...
いや あるのか…。
No, there's something...
今回の任務…
つうか あの忍描のことだけどよ→
This current mission...
Rather, that Ninja Cat.
ソイツが ちょっと
特殊な猫らしいんだわ。
It seems that cat is pretty special.
はあ？ アンタいつから
猫博士になったとね？
Huh? Since when are you
a cat expert?
そんなんじゃねえ！
俺らの一族の長…。
I'm not!
The leader of our clan...
つうか 親父が病気でよ。
I mean, my dad's sick...
治療の漢方薬に
その忍描のヒゲがいるらしいんだわ。
The medicine for his treatment
calls for some of
that Ninja Cat's whiskers.
なら 取ったらいいっちゃない？
Then you should take some, right?
い いいよな？
It's okay, right?
知らん。
I dunno.
知らん振りばしとっちゃるけん→
Keep me in the dark.
知らんとこで取ったら
よかろうもん。
If you take it without my knowing,
it's okay.
お そうだ
アイツにだけは絶対 言うな！
That's true.
Just don't tell you-know-who!
はぁ～？ ケツの穴の小さか男やね。
Huh? Talk about being a coward!
そげん年下のイタチが飛び級で→
Are you that jealous because Itachi,
who's way younger than you,
しかも 首席で卒業したのが
悔しかとね～？
skipped a bunch of grades
and graduated first in class?
(テンマ)あ アイツがいなけりゃ…。
(シンコ)は？ アンタが首席やったと？
– If it wasn't for him...
– What? You'd be ranked at the top?
(テンマ)そ そんなことを
言ってんじゃねえ！
I didn't say that!
(シンコ)はいは～い。
Yeah, yeah...
(シンコ)イタチはすごかけんね～。
Anyway, Itachi sure is awesome...
張り合っても…。
(テンマ)張り合ってねえし！
There's no point in
competing with him.
I'm not competing with him!
(シンコ)はあ？
(テンマ)首席だからどうとか…。
And it has nothing to do
with being top-ranked!
忍描の居場所がわかりました。
We've found out the location
of the Ninja Cat.
水無月先生と合流してください。
Please regroup
with Minazuki Sensei.
(忍描)ニャー フラれちゃったニャー。
Ah, rejected again!
(忍描)一族の連中め。
And the clan just keeps harping on
about me getting married...
CATNIP LIQUOR
嫁とれ 嫁とれ
うるさいんだニャ！ ヒック。
(シンコ)はは～ん
メス猫の尻ば追いかけて→
So he was chasing
around some female cat
こげんとこまで来よったっちゃね。
and ended up here of all places...
(ユウキ)ま そういうことみたいだね。
Seems like it.
任務は完了したようなもんだが…。
It seems as though our mission
is complete, but...
よし 僕が行こう
みんなはここで待機。
Okay, I'll go.
Everyone, hang back here.
(ユウキ)やあ！
ニャンだ？
Hey!
What do you want?
キミの話を聞いて
たいへん共感したもんだから→
I just overheard your story
and I sympathize,
もう少し話をしたいと思ってね。
so I wanted to talk.
おミャーにわかるのニャ？
Can you even understand
the feelings of a male cat
振られたオス猫の気持がニャー！
who's been rejected meow?
わかる！ わかるよ その気持。
I do! I do understand
that feeling!
ハハハハ…。
そうか！ おミャーもモテないくちニャ！
I see...
So you're not popular
with the ladies either.
うっ…。
(ユウキ)そうなんですよ…。
Uh... yeah, that's it.
(忍猫)まぁ 一杯 飲むニャ。
Well, have a drink meow.
まったく
わかっちゃいないんすよね。
They just don't understand
a male's charm.
男の魅力ってやつを。
(ユウキ)これだから 女ってやつは
人を見る目がないというか→
That's why ladies just
don't have perspective...
男を見る目がないというか…。
or rather a discerning eye...
彼女の悪口言うニャ！
Don't insult her!
交渉決裂のようですね。
Looks like there's a breakdown
in communications.
ったく 最初から
こいつでよかったんだよ！
Damn it!
We should have done this
from the start!
ニャンだ？ 小僧ども。
What's going on meow,
you brats?
相手になってやるニャ！
I'll take you on meow!
逃がすか！
You're not getting away!
野郎！ 先回りのつもりか!?
Damn it, he's going on ahead?!
(テンマ)ぐわっ！
うっ！
(シンコ)キャー！
に… 肉球 モフモフ…。
His paw... fluffy... fluffy...
やるな。
He's pretty good.
《まずは あの機動力を
なんとかしないと…》
We have to do something
about his mobility first...
《あのシッポで
バランスをとっているんだな。
He's balancing himself with his tail.
でも それだけじゃない。
But that's not all...
あのヒゲが
空間認識力を高めているんだ。
Those whiskers enhance
his spatial perception.
なら…》
In that case...!
(忍猫)どこ狙ってるニャン。
What are you aiming at meow?
なかなかのクナイさばきニャが
まだまだニャ。
You're pretty good with the kunai,
but you've still a ways to go, meow.
ああ そうだね。 あと５ミリは
刈り取れると思っていたよ。
Yeah, you're right.
I thought I could have managed
five millimeters more...
えっ？
Huh?!
ニャー！
こっちは うまくいったけど
間に合うかな？
Things went well here...
But will it be in time?
早駆けのテンマ様をなめんなよ！
Don't underestimate
Speedy Tenma!
ハハッ これ ケガじゃすまねえかも…。
This may end up causing
more than just a scratch...
ん？ うおっ！
よかった どっちも間に合って。
I'm glad we were
in time for both!
ハハッ ハハ… やったぜ。
I... did it!
この度は お世話になったニャ。
Thank you for your help.
確かに 早く身をかためニャとは
言ったニャけど…。
I did tell him to hurry up
and settle down...
まさか 猫妻に惚れるなんて。
But I never expected him
to fall in love...
コイツは 腕は立つくせに
メスを見る目がニャくて。
This one has good skills,
but no eye for judging females.
一族のために 最高の嫁さんを
探したつもりだったのニャ。
I just wanted to find the best bride
for the sake of our clan.
ニャにはともあれ
無事でよかったニャ。
The most important thing
is that you're okay.
確かに 依頼どおり 任務
ご苦労さんと言いたいとこだけど。
You fulfilled the mission just
as I requested...
is what I'd like to say...
あれのヒゲ どうした？
But what happened
to his whiskers?
(イタチ)必要最小限の
戦闘にとどめるために→
To keep the fighting to a minimum,
there was no choice.
しかたなかったんです。
(猫バア)切ったのかい！ はぁ…。
So you cut them?
まあ そいつの価値を
言ってなかったのは→
Well, it's my fault for not giving you
a heads up on his skills...
こっちも悪かったんだけど…。
拾ってこなかったのかい？
You didn't bring them back?
はい 風に流れて 奈落に…。
No... they blew away in the wind.
はぁ しかたないか。
任務 ご苦労さん。
Well, I guess it can't be helped.
Thank you for your efforts.
イタチ 次に来るときは
うちはの たまってるツケを→
Itachi...
Next time you come,
I'll have you take care
of the debts the Uchiha
have racked up.
たっぷり払ってもらうからね。
(イタチ)ハハハ…。
(シンコ)ほしかったもんが
手に入って よかったやん。
Good thing you got
what you needed, eh?
まあな。
Well, yeah...
もっと嬉しそうな顔せんね。
Cheer up, will ya?
一族の運命が かかっとるとやろ？
The fate of your clan rests on it, right?
そこまで 大げさじゃねえよ。
It's not that critical!
けど これで 親父もよくなれば
一族も まだまだ 安泰だ。
But...
If this cures my dad,
my clan will be secure.
《イタチ : あの忍猫も
あの大人たちも→
That Ninja Cat...
And those grownups...
みんな 一族のためを
思っているんだよな》
They're all thinking about their clans...
テメエ 俺を助けた気に
なってんじゃねえぞ。
You'd better not be thinking
that you saved me.
そんなつもりはないです。
The thought hasn't crossed my mind.
オメエの助けなんか なくたってな！
Even if you didn't end up
helping me...
くっ… 何しやがる。
What are you doing?!
アンタ まだ
そげなことば言いよると。
Why are you still
saying stuff like that?
仲間やけん
助けるとは当たり前やん。
He's your friend!
Of course, he's going to help you!
はぁ 仲間？
俺は任務を遂行しただけで…。
– Huh?! Me? His friend?!
– I was just fulfilling my mission.
俺が コイツと？
うっ！
アンタも難しいことば言わんと。
You stop being
so difficult as well!
ほれ
イタチに言うことがあるっちゃろ。
All right! Isn't there something
you want to say to Itachi?!
この借りは必ず返すからな。
I swear I'll make it up
to you for this!
素直に 「ありがとね」って
言えばよかったい。
Why can't you just
say thank you?!
ぐぉ～っ シンコ 痛すぎだろう！
Shinko, that hurt too much!
《仲間か…》
Friend, huh?
(サスケ)兄さん これ何？
Big Brother! What is this?
これは あのときの…。
This is... from that time...
《イタチ : 命は生まれ 命は死ぬ。
Life is born, and life dies...
だが 救われるのも また命。
But life is saved again...
いや あのときアイツを助けたのは→
Wait...
When I saved him back then,
そんなに深い思いが
あったわけじゃない》
I didn't think too deeply about it.
((仲間やけん
助けるとは当たり前やん))
He's your friend!
Of course,
he's going to help you!
《イタチ : 一族が集い 里が生まれ
そして 関わった者たち。
A clan grows...
A village is born...
And bonds are made...
それを仲間と言うのなら
確かに俺たちは仲間だった。
If that's what friends are...
We were friends, no doubt about it.
関わってしまったから
あんなことに…》
We formed a bond...
That's why that happened...
《イタチ : 関わってしまったから
アイツは…》
We had a bond...
That's why he...
((テンマ : この借りは
必ず返すからな))
I swear I'll make it up
to you for this!
《イタチ : 死んだんだ。
... died.
俺には わかってなかった。
I didn't understand back then...
本当の痛みが。
What real pain was.
命を失うという痛みが。
The pain of losing a life...
失って初めて知った。
I felt it for the first time
after losing it...
いや 気づかされた。
No, I was made to realize it...
大切なものを
失いたくないという気持に…》
The feeling of not wanting
to lose something precious.
兄さん 目が…。
Big Brother!
Your eyes!
《お前も いつか→
Will the day come when
you'll possess these eyes too?
この目を持つ日がくるんだろうか。
この悲しみを知る日が…》
The day when you come
to know what sadness is?
sonna kimi o nazeka
I don't know why but someone like me
konna boku wa zutto hitei dekinakute
just couldn't reject someone like you
hashitteiru sono senaka o
So I kept running after you
taiyou mitai ni oikaketa
like you were the sun
te ga todokisou na yume wa kachi ga nainda
A dream that's within reach doesn't have any value
zettai ni muri datte iwareru kurai ga ii
I like it better when I'm told it's unreachable
akirameru nante itsudatte dekiru kara
I can give up any time I want
hikihanasaretemo boku wa ganbarou
so I'll keep trying no matter how much we're pulled apart
hito wa doushite ase nagashite kisoiau no ka?
Why do people sweat and fight so hard?
jibun no sonzai o shoumei shitai
I want to prove that I exist
sonna kimi wa kitto
That someone like you has a fear
konna boku niwa nai kodoku ni obieterunda
of being alone that someone like me doesn't have
sono saki niwa daremo inai
There's no one beyond that point
ushiro ni chikadzuku fuan dake
As anxiety closes in from behind
boku ga iru
I will be there
All right, I'll be going.
Big Brother!
You promised we'd play today!
うわぁ～ きれいになったこと！
That's right!
But I have a mission.
５ヵ月マチで手にした涙涙の宝物。
Forgive me, Sasuke... Next time.
Sorry about that, Sasuke.
ワオ！
I'm going to borrow your brother
for a little bit.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Shisui's Request"
１年マチでイギリス人が
手にしたザ・ニッポン！
11年と５ヵ月マチになってます。
Sasuke was glaring at me too!
11年５ヵ月マチのグルメとは!?